Barry Wang (PMP, Prince2, ITIL, CSM, MSP)

Senior Project Manager

Certified Senior Project Manager with over 10 years of experience in cloud/IT infrastructure, CDN, tele-communication and network, consulting and system integration, software development in small to large, complex environment.

Managed multi strategically important projects with sound business consulting skill and diverse technical background. Leader, mentor and team player interfacing with all levels of management and stakeholders.

Phone: +64273651442/+8613811097069 Email: barry.wang.hd@gmail.com WebSite: www.barry.wang.hd@gmail.com

EXPERTISE

- > Strategic Planning and Management: Took program director role managing key programs from end to end perspective including creating statement of work, managing stakeholders, defining delivery strategy, controlling delivery according to baselines and in the most cost/time effective way. Helped account teams to achieve business targets in 5 extremely tough projects
- ➤ Handling Multi Projects with Details: In charge of cloud infrastructure projects in BJS/PEK region and managing all CDN/DX infrastructure builds around APAC in AWS. Successfully managed over 18 projects/programs in Ericsson involving diverse solution and multi countries.
- ➤ **Team building/leadership:** Built up competence of charging, Voice over LTE and cloud(NFV) for local key resources. Combined project goal and personal development of team members to reach win-win situation. Led the project team of 40+ members including subproject managers.
- ➤ **Continues Improvement**: Innovatively introduced agile methodology to service delivery resulting in 10% efficiency improved regarding man effort involved. Kept coaching team's mind set of quality and used bottom-up approach turning around a vital project at risk.
- ➤ **Knowledge Sharing & Team Collaboration**: Used SharePoint to manage projects, facilitate team collaboration, share information and knowledge. Created reused SharePoint web template for large scale projects. Presented project experience in Ericsson global seminars.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Project Management Methodologies, Agile, SDLC, Microsoft Project, Office Suite, SharePoint
- > Cloud, Telecommunication, Network, NFV, VoLTE, BSS, OSS, CDN, Data Centre Infrastructure

CERTIFICATES

- > PMP Project Management Professional
- Prince2 (Practitioner) Projects in a Controlled Environment
- > MSP (Practitioner) Managing Successful Programmes
- CSM Certified Scrum Master
- > ITIL Foundation Certified Version 3
- Ericsson Certified Senior Project Manager for Consulting and System Integration.

Certificates & Awards scanned: http://www.barry.wang/Certificates.html

Project management reference for one of my strategic projects: http://www.barry.wang/Project.html

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Amazon Web Service Technical Program Manager 2015 to Present

- > Develop and manage all infrastructure projects in BJS/PEK region to enhance infrastructure and its operations including new data centre design, construction, mechanical and electrical equipment, power and cooling, security, network deployment, expansion and migration etc.
- ➤ Act as a bridge between infrastructure teams on the ground and business teams to ensure that stringent standards are met in the most cost-efficient way. Successfully handled all pull-in requests so far to meet high customer demands in BJS region.
- Manage CDN/DX infrastructure builds (new site, expansion, refresh, network scaling) around APAC as portfolio manager. Define delivery strategy, governance projects owned by different project managers around APAC, prioritize resources and escalate key issues to Seattle.
 - **Projects & Achievements:** BJS region expansion & New Site, PEK Site Exit & Migration.

Ericsson Region North East Asia Senior Project Manager 2007 to 2015

- > Started from access level project manager to senior level by delivering increasingly complex projects and passing certification program step by step. Selected as role model mentoring project managers in 3 project offices transferring to new way of project management.
- Successfully managed over 18 projects/programs end to end for different operators in China, Tai Wan, Hong Kong, Japan and Singapore including creating SOW, planning, scoping, costing, controlling, managing changes, risks, stakeholders, supplier/subcontractor etc.
- > Contract value ranged up to 10M USD. Solution areas involved network rollout, business and operation consulting, system integration, software development of different scales.

Projects & Achievements:

- ➤ China Mobile NFV virtualized IMS (IAAS) Project. Directed the efforts of sub-project managers, system architects, developers, and system integrators to pass trail test with limited global support. Kept Ericsson in the engagement of China Mobile telecom cloud transformation with positive feedback from customer. Built up local resources' competence of cloud by leveraging the possible channels and team self-learning.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone VolTE (Voice over LTE i.e. 4G) Project. Served as program director to negotiate scope, beat competitors, secure contract finally. Led a cross-functional team of over 40 members to realize and deploy this complex solution integrating with 2G/3G/4G. Ericsson first commercial launched VolTE in this region. Achieved 15% margin improved, shared as best practice and contributed to Ericsson's VolTE blueprint. Developed AP/GW solution (AIS, Linux, Oracle, MySQL, C/C++, JAVA, Tomcat, struts2, Mina) which have been reused by 4 different markets. Helped SmarTone become one of the first authorized Iphone6 operators around the world.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone MPBN/PRAN QoS (Quality of Services) Project. Managed design and implementation of E2E QoS for live IP infrastructure (switches, routers, firewalls) and Core/RAN nodes of 2G/3G. Performed QoS audit to align the policy end to end.
- ➤ China Mobile MBC (Mobile Broadband Charging) Consulting Project. Took project manager and business analysis role providing technology consulting about mobile broadband charging for coming 4G services. Provided PoC based on 3PP BCS (Telcordia Broadband

- Charging System) solution in live network. Agile development for the special requirements.
- ➤ Japan SoftBank OSS(Operation Support System) ENIC development. Led team to enhance the data analysis function of the current OSS system, develop separate requirements for KPI analysis and distribution. Secured another 2 Purchase Orders for new requirements.
- ➤ China Mobile e-Channel Consulting Project. Took project manager and business analysis role to re-engineer business process of customer's e-channel to address the increasing requirements of online business. Defined technical specification to improve the current CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system regarding product management, payment etc. Secured successive contract to develop and deliver the online payment gateway.
- ➤ Hong Kong SmarTone Proof of Concept for Charging System. Demonstrated and convinced rigorous SmarTone of system's flexibility and functionality by leveraging local development competence in an E2E (End to End) POC based on Ericsson Charging System within a tight schedule.
- ➤ China Mobile Awareness of Charging. Led customer engagement by initiating a small field trial convincing customer the benefit of real time notification. Then turned into commercial contract as online charging gateway serving 22.8M subscribers in HLJ and 6.8M subscriber in LN. Developed online charging gateway (Linux, MySQL, C/C++, JAVA, Tomcat, struts2, Mina).
- ➤ China Mobile (M2M) Machine to Machine for 2 provinces. Managed partner to deliver first 2 commercial M2M contracts providing the platform for potential industries. Led partner and customer to analyse business requirements, find industry application, and define business cases.
- ➤ China Unicom 2G/3G device Management for 11 provinces. Leveraged customer requirement and Ericsson experience in device management to work out the local solution. Managed team to develop a new system and deliver the solution in 11 provinces. Outsourced most of the development and delivery tasks to 3PP and took the key role by Ericsson.
- ➤ China Netcom Integrated Service Platform for 4 provinces. Transformed part of business support system from traditional vertical architecture to flat one. Provided transitional consulting for the operation. Managed delivery of 4 provinces as the program manager.

Check out more projects

Crossbow Technology Inc. Team Lead 2006-2007

- > Drove firmware development and migration among different hardware platforms for machine to machine solution to meet different customer requirements.
- Coordinated software and hardware team customizing solution for mine and land monitoring. **Projects & Achievements:** Platform Migration, Auto-Testing System, Land Monitoring

Lucent Technology Inc. Technical Project Manager 1998-2001

- > Started as an engineer deploying 5ESS (#5 Electronic Switch System) and gained technical reputation very soon, then led projects technical troubleshooting and contractor training.
- > Successfully delivered very large scale network rollout in 3 different big cities as a technical project manager in charge of planning, logistics, installation, acceptance and handover etc.
 - Projects & Achievements: PHS rollout, One Tel Australia MSC, and Network Migration

Awards & Trainings & Educations

Awards

- Excellent Employee of Ericsson North East Asia in 2009 and 2012
- Excellent Team Award CNC Integrated Service Platform 1.0 Phase 2 Rollout in 2008
- Excellent Employee of Lucent Tsing Dao in 1999 and 2000

Trainings

- ➤ Leadership for Professionals / Leadership for Project Managers
- > SI Campus/Enjoy Customer Service
- > Way to Ericsson Agile leader/ Way to Ericsson Coacher/ Kan Ban/This is Lean
- > AWS Business Professional/AWS technical Professional/Making Great Hiring Decisions

Educations

- 2003–2006 Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Science Master in Computer Networks and Multimedia Communication
- > 1994–1998 Ocean University of China Bachelor of Computer Software (Minored in Law)